<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <!-- Application name -->
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">CDMDDA</string>

    <!-- App Text   -->
    <string name="ui_text_login">Login</string>
    <string name="ui_text_register">Register</string>
    <string name="ui_text_logout">Logout</string>
    <string name="ui_text_main">Welcome to CDMDDA</string>
    <string name="ui_user_guest">Guest</string>

    <!-- BUTTON:title texts -->
    <string name="ui_text_camera">From Camera</string>
    <string name="ui_text_gallery">From Gallery</string>
    <string name="ui_text_cancel">Cancel</string>

    <!-- TITLE texts -->
    <string name="ui_head_account">Accounts</string>

    <!-- MENU_ITEM:title texts -->
    <string name="ui_text_search">Search</string>
    <string name="ui_text_account" translatable="false">Account</string>
    <string name="ui_text_settings" translatable="false">Settings</string>

    <!-- MENU_ITEM:contentDescription texts -->
    <string name="ui_desc_search">More crop disease information</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_account">Login or Register account</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_settings">Personalize the app</string>

    <!-- DESCRIPTION texts -->
    <string name="ui_desc_login">Login to carry over your diagnosis and search history across multiple devices.</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_register">Register an account to save and access your data on any device.</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_logout">Are you sure? Subsequent diagnosis and search queries will not be saved</string>

    <string name="ui_text_diseases">Diseases</string>
    <string name="ui_text_crops">Crops</string>
    <string name="ui_text_today">Today</string>
    <string name="ui_hint_search">Search diseases</string>

    <!-- InferenceDialog -->
    <string name="ui_text_result">Result</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_diagnosis_fail">Unable to diagnose</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_diagnosis_fail">No leaf or disease detected</string>
    <string name="ui_text_analyzing">Analyzing…</string>
    <string name="ui_head_search">Showing results for</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_search">No results found</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_history">No diagnosis found</string>

    <!-- Settings -->
    <string name="ui_head_customization">Customization</string>
    <string name="ui_text_theme" translatable="false">Theme</string>
    <string name="ui_text_language">Language</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_lang">Choose Language</string>
    <string name="ui_head_personal">Personal Data</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_diagnosis">Clear Diagnosis History</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_clear_diagnosis">Erase all of the recorded diagnosis of this account permanently</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_search">Clear Search History</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_clear_search">Erase all of the search queries made in this account permanently</string>
    <!-- SettingsDialog -->
    <string name="ui_warn_clear_diagnosis">Are you sure? All recorded diagnosis will be lost permanently</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_clear_search">Are you sure? All searched queries will be lost permanently</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_diagnosis_success">Diagnosis history cleared</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_search_success">Search history cleared</string>

    <string name="ui_text_symptoms">Symptoms</string>
    <string name="ui_text_treatment">Treatment</string>
    <string name="ui_text_cause">Cause</string>


    <string name="ui_desc_img_toolbar" translatable="false">Crop Image</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_img_disease" translatable="false">Disease Image</string>

    <string name="ui_hint_diagnose">You can now diagnose possible plant diseases with just a leaf picture. Try and submit an image from your phone camera/gallery</string>


    <!-- Variables -->
    <string name="val_labels" translatable="false">labels.txt</string>
    <string name="var_dataset" translatable="false" tools:ignore="Typos">set1</string>
    <string name="var_dim" translatable="false">224</string>
    <string name="val_healthy" translatable="false">Healthy</string>
    <string name="val_activity_settings" translatable="false">SettingsActivity</string>

    <!-- Dataset -->
    <string name="val_vector_fungi" translatable="false">Fungi</string>
    <string name="val_vector_pest" translatable="false">Pest</string>
    <string name="val_vector_bacteria" translatable="false">Bacteria</string>

    <string name="disease_bacterial_spot" translatable="false">Bacterial Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_common_rust" translatable="false">Common Rust</string>
    <string name="disease_cercospora_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Cercospora Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_septoria_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Septoria Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_northern_leaf_blight" translatable="false">Northern Leaf Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_early_blight" translatable="false">Early Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_late_blight" translatable="false">Late Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_powdery_mildew" translatable="false">Powdery Mildew</string>
    <string name="disease_leaf_mold" translatable="false">Leaf Mold</string>
    <string name="disease_spider_mite" translatable="false">Spider Mite</string>
    <string name="disease_target_spot" translatable="false">Target Spot</string>

    <string name="crop_id_bell_pepper" translatable="false">Bell Pepper</string>
    <string name="crop_id_corn" translatable="false">Corn</string>
    <string name="crop_id_potato" translatable="false">Potato</string>
    <string name="crop_id_squash" translatable="false">Squash</string>
    <string name="crop_id_tomato" translatable="false">Tomato</string>
    <string name="crop_name_bell_pepper">Bell Pepper</string>
    <string name="crop_name_corn">Corn</string>
    <string name="crop_name_potato">Potato</string>
    <string name="crop_name_squash">Squash</string>
    <string name="crop_name_tomato">Tomato</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_bell_pepper" translatable="false">Capsicum anuum</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_corn" translatable="false">Zea mays</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_potato" translatable="false">Solanum tuberosum</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_squash" translatable="false">Cucurbita maxima</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_tomato" translatable="false">Solanum lycopersicum</string>

    <string name="crop_desc_bell_pepper">Bell peppers (Capsicum anuum) locally known as “Alsal”, is a member of the
        capsicum family, which includes mild peppers, have a mild, sweet flavor and crisp, juicy flesh. According to
        foodfacts.com, bell peppers do not have a significant level of spiciness when compared to other peppers. Red
        bell peppers, as well as some yellow and orange types, are sweeter. Pepper plant seedlings should always be
        started indoors. To germinate, the seeds require the warmth of your home. Fill a seed tray halfway with seed
        starting soil or well-draining potting soil, then fill each container with one to three seeds. Place the tray in
        a warm location or use a warming pad to keep it between 70- and 90-degrees Fahrenheit. (21-32 C.) – the warmer
        the better. They are high in vitamin A, vitamin C, and potassium. Bell peppers also provide a good source of
        fiber, folate, and iron. Bell peppers, in addition to being high in nutrients, provide a pleasant and
        low-calorie crunch with every bite.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_corn">Corn (Zea mays) locally known as “Mais” is a large grain plant came from the grass
        family and a native to Central America, but it is now cultivated all around the world. It has six major types
        including popcorn, flour corn, dent corn, sweet corn, pod corn, and flint corn. This popular cereal grain has
        numerous purposes, but it is mostly used for culinary purposes. It is usually eaten boiled, grilled, and
        ingredients in cooking some of our favorite dishes. It has been also used to make corn flour, cornmeal, corn
        oil, corn syrup, tortilla chips, and other corn processed products. It contains dietary fiber, calories,
        carbohydrates, proteins, omega-3 fatty acids, and other nutrients. It has vitamins A, B, E, pantothenic acid,
        riboflavin, niacin, folate, and thiamine. It has minerals such as copper, potassium, iron, phosphorus, zinc,
        manganese, calcium, and magnesium. Corn plants are tall, therefore if placed on the north side, they will not
        cast shadows on other garden plants, reducing plant productivity. The ideal temperature range is 60 to 85
        degrees Fahrenheit. Temperatures below 50 degrees F. Corn is not going to grow. Plants should be spaced 8 to 10
        inches apart. Plant hills 2 to 3 feet apart with 3 to 4 plants per hill as an alternative configuration.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_potato">Potato (Solanum tuberosum L.). locally known as ‘patatas\", is a root vegetable
        native to the Americas, with the plant itself being a perennial in the nightshade family Solanaceae. It includes
        high levels of vitamin B-complex as well as vitamin C. A potato has more vitamin C than other fruits. Potatoes
        also contain a variety of minerals, including potassium, magnesium, phosphorus, iron, and calcium. Every mineral
        has its own function in keeping the body healthy. Potatoes are also high in fiber, which gives you a sensation
        of fullness and aids digestion. When potatoes are cooked with their skins on, they retain the majority of their
        fiber. Potato can reach a height of 100 cm (40 inches). As the potato plant matures, its compound leaves produce
        starch, which is then transmitted to the tips of its underground stems. The stems thicken to develop a few or up
        to 20 tubers near the soil surface.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_squash">Squash (Cucurbita maxima), locally known as “kalabasa”, is an annual herbaceous vine
        that can grow to be four meters long or more. It has a huge fruit with a yellow, meaty inside and is a popular
        vegetable in Filipino recipes like ginataang kalabasa and pinakbet. It is high in vitamin A, which is beneficial
        for maintaining eye health, boosting the immune system, and supporting cell growth among others. When producing
        squash, it is crucial to know that this food develops best in soils rich in organic material, according to the
        Agricultural Training Institute in the Cordillera Administrative Region (ATI-CAR). It is also fruitful all year,
        especially in areas with temperatures ranging from 18 to 30 degrees Celsius.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_tomato">Tomato (Solanum lycopersicum), locally known as \"Kamatis\", is a savory, often red,
        edible fruit that grows on a plant. Tomato fruit is consumed in a variety of ways, including raw, as a component
        in numerous meals and sauces, and in beverages. While it is botanically a fruit, it is regarded as a vegetable
        in the culinary world, which has caused some confusion. The tomato is a member of the nightshade family. The
        plants normally develop to a height of 1–3 meters (3–10 ft) and have a weak, woody stem that vines over adjacent
        plants. It is a perennial, although often grown outdoors in temperate climates as an annual. Tomatoes are a top
        source of vitamins A and C. It also has a lot of fiber, beta-carotene, iron, lycopene, magnesium, niacin,
        potassium, phosphorus, riboflavin, and thiamine. Tomatoes have low levels of saturated fat, cholesterol, and
        salt. Moreover, unlike other foods, tomato cooking or processing (tomato paste, catsup, tomato soup, tomato
        sauce) is favorable to health. When tomatoes are heated, their cell walls break down, releasing more lycopene, a
        phytochemical that is beneficial to our health.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_cause_bacterial_spot">The bacterium Xanthomonas campestris py.vescatoria causes bacteria leaf
        spot. It thrives in areas with hot summers and frequent rainfall.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_spot">Once the symptoms of bacterial leaf spot begin to appear on your
        pepper plants, it’s too late to save them. However, if you take precautions before planting next season, you’ll
        have a better chance of preventing peppery leaf spot problems in the future. Crop rotation can help prevent
        bacterial leaf spot. Do not plant peppers or tomatoes in a location where either of these crops has been grown
        in the past four or five years. At the end of the season, remove all crop debris from the garden and destroy it.
        Do not compost plant debris that may contain the disease. Once the area is clean of all visible debris, till the
        soil or turn it with a shovel to bury any remaining bacteria. The bacterium is spread by splattering damp soil
        onto the leaves. Reduce the splatter by using a soaker hose and avoiding overhead watering. Stay out of the
        garden on wet days to avoid spreading disease on your hands and clothes. Bacterial leaf spot is also spread
        through infected seeds. Buy certified disease-free seeds and seedlings. It’s best not to save your own seeds if
        you’ve ever had a problem with bacterial leaf spot on peppers.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_spot_1">These lesions normally begin on the lower leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_cercospora_leaf_spot">Causes severe yield loss in cowpea.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_cercospora_leaf_spot">Use resistant varieties, If available. Disinfect tools used in
        an infested field. Crop rotation with rice and corn for at least 3-5 years may help reduce inoculum in the soil.
        Use resistant/moderately verities, if available.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_1">Leaves and fruit can be affected particularly in hot humid
        conditions.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_2">Leaf spots begin as small, round , brown, lesions and often
        with white/light brown center.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_3">Some spots are surrounded by a distinct yellow halo.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_4">Under the warm and wet condition, the lesions expand and the
        leaves may appear blighted.
    </string>

    <string name="disease_vector_bacterial_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_bacteria</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_cercospora_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_common_rust">Common rust is caused by the fungus Puccinia sorghi and occurs every
        growing season. It is seldom a concern in hybrid corn.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_common_rust_1">The disease by the development of dark, reddish-brown pustules
        (uredinia) scattered over both the upper and lower surfaces of the corn leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_common_rust_2">These pustules may appear on any above ground part of the plant, but
        are most abundant on the leaves. Pustules appear oval to elongate in shape, are generally small, less than 1/4
        inch long, and are surrounded by the leaf epidermal layer, where it has broken through.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_common_rust_3">If infections occur while the leaves are still in the whorl, these
        pustules may develop in bands across the surface as the leaf expands in size.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_common_rust">Plant resistant varieties(if available). Plow in old crops as soon as
        harvesting and ensure all crop is decomposed before panting.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_cause_early_blight">The diseases are caused by the fungus Alternaria solani.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_early_blight_1">Dark spots with concentric growth and yellow halos on leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_early_blight_2">Leaves dry out and fall, fruits may start to rot and eventually
        drop.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_early_blight">Use pathogen-free seed, or collect seed only from disease-free plants.
        Rotate out of tomatoes and related crops for at least two years. Control susceptible weeds such as black
        nightshade and hairy nightshade, and volunteer tomato plants throughout the rotation. Fertilize properly to
        maintain vigorous plant growth. Particularly, do not over-fertilize with potassium and maintain adequate levels
        of both nitrogen and phosphorus. Avoid working in plants when they are wet from rain, irrigation, or dew. Use
        drip irrigation instead of overhead irrigation to keep foliage dry. Stake the plants to increase airflow around
        the plant and facilitate drying. Staking will also reduce contact between the leaves and spore-contaminated
        soil. Apply plastic or organic mulch to reduce humidity and provide a barrier between contaminated soil and
        leaves. In the fall, remove or bury infected plants to reduce the likelihood of the pathogen surviving to the
        following year. For greenhouse production, early blight has been reduced by as much as 50% by covering houses
        with UV-absorbing vinyl film.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_common_rust" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_early_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_late_blight">Late blight is caused by the oomycete Phytophthora infestans. Oomycetes are
        fungus-like organisms also called water molds, but they are not true fungi. There are many different strains of
        P. infestans. Many clonal lineages affect both tomato and potato, but some lineages are specific to one host or
        the other.The host range is typically limited to potato and tomato, but hairy nightshade (Solanum physalifolium)
        is a closely related weed that can readily become infected and may contribute to disease spread. Under ideal
        conditions, such as a greenhouse, petunia also may become infected.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_late_blight_1">Dark brown spots on leaf tips, Spots turn into transparent wounds.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_late_blight_2">White fungus covers the underside of leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_late_blight_3">Leaves wilt and die off, Grayish-blue spots on potato tubers.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_late_blight">Avoid overhead irrigation/watering and overwatering of transplants. The
        bacterial speck and spot pathogens can be spread easily in the greenhouse when plant density is high and plant
        are watered overhead. Minimize overwatering transplant in the greenhouse and overhead watering when possible.
        Avoiding excessive handling of transplants. Bacteria can easily be spread on tools and on worker’s hands. Avoid
        handing transplant more than necessary, especially when wet. Choose, prepare, and maintain an appropriate field
        for planting tomatoes in soil that drains well. Remove voluntary tomatoes and from the fields before planting
        and during crop rotation years when non-host crops are planted.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_late_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_leaf_mold">The fungus passalora fulva causes leaf mold.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_1">Starts as pale green to yellowish spot-on upper leaf surfaces that turn a
        bright yellow.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_2">The spots merge as the disease progresses and the foliage then dies.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_3">Infected leaves curl, wither, and often drop from the plant. Flowers,
        stems, and fruit that maybe infected, although usually only leaf tissue is infected.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_4">When the disease does manifest on the fruit, tomatoes with leaf mold
        become dark in color, leathery, and root and stem end.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mold">Although infected seed is frequently the primary source of the disease,
        it can also be found in diseased plant waste or in the soil. Rain and wind spread the disease, as do tools and
        clothing, as well as insect activity. High relative humidity (more than 85%) paired with high temperatures
        promotes disease spread. Keeping this in mind, if you\'re growing tomatoes in a greenhouse, keep the night
        temperatures higher than the outside temperatures. Use only certified disease-free or treated seed when sowing.
        After harvest, remove and discard any crop trash. Between crop seasons, sanitize the greenhouse. To reduce leaf
        moisture, use fans and prevent overhead watering. Plants should also be staked and pruned to improve
        ventilation. If the disease is detected, use a fungicide as directed by the manufacturer at the first sign of
        infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_leaf_mold" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_northern_leaf_blight">It is causes by another fungus that overwinters in infested crop
        debris. The tan lesions can be small to very large and elliptical in shape, usually with smooth round ends.
        Mature lesions in humid conditions may appear duty in the middle as the fungus produces spores that are spread
        to the other leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_northern_leaf_blight_1">In a susceptible hybrid is one to sixth inches long
        cigar-shaped.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_northern_leaf_blight_2">The first appear as small light green to grayish spots
        approximately 1-2 weeks after infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_northern_leaf_blight_3">As the disease develops, the lesions spread to all leafy
        structures, including the husks, and produce dark spores, giving lesions as dirty appearance.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_northern_leaf_blight">Control of this disease is often focused on management and
        prevention. First, choose corn varieties or hybrids that are resistant or at least have moderate resistance to
        northern corn leaf blight. When you grow corn, make sure it does not stay wet for long periods of time. The
        fungus that causes this infection needs between six and 18 hours of leaf wetness to develop. Plant corn with
        enough space for airflow and water in the morning so leaves can dry throughout the day. The fungus overwinters
        in plant material, so it is also important to manage infected plants. Tilling the corn into the soil is one
        strategy, but with a small garden it may make more sense to just remove and destroy the affected plants.
        Treating northern corn leaf blight involves using fungicides. For most home gardeners this step isn’t needed,
        but if you have a bad infection, you may want to try this chemical treatment. The infection usually begins
        around the time of silking, and this is when the fungicide should be applied.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_northern_leaf_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_powdery_mildew">It causes several different species of fungus. Each species has its own
        preferred host plants. The species od powdery mildew that affects squash foliage (Erysiphe cichacearum) is
        different from those that target peas (Erysiphe pisi). Interestingly, this fungus lives on the outside of the
        leaves and does not penetrate the internal tissue. It can only grow on the surface of the leaf.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_powdery_mildew_1">The symptoms are the small, white, dusty spots on the young leaves
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_powdery_mildew_2">Initially, there will only be a few spots, but it spreads quickly,
        eventually covering the entire leaf surface.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_powdery_mildew_3">Powdery mildew is most commonly seen on the top of the leaves, but
        it can also appear on the leaf undersides, the stem, and even on the fruits.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_powdery_mildew">Don’t touch infected leaves and then touch the healthy leaves.
        You’ve just spread spores. Always plant squash in the full sun. shady conditions are more humid and that
        encourage spore germination. Cut off any leaves that show early signs of infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_powdery_mildew" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_septoria_leaf_spot">Causes of fungus: Septoria lycospersici can destroy tomato foliage
        and reduce yield. Through fruit infection is uncommon, the destruction of foliage can lead to fruit failure or
        make fruit prone to sunscald.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_septoria_leaf_spot_1">It develop on the calyx, leaves, and stems round lesions with
        dark margins and tan gray center develop on leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_septoria_leaf_spot_2">Black fruiting bodies(pycnidia) develop in center of lesions
        approximately 2 weeks after infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_septoria_leaf_spot_3">A thin, yellow halo often develops around lesions on leaflets.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_septoria_leaf_spot">Crops rotation, weed management, cultural practices, sanitation,
        fungicides
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_septoria_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_spider_mite">Spider mite feeding can cause numerous yellow or white tiny granulated
        spots on tomato leaves. The infestation mostly occurs under hot and dry conditions
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_spider_mite_1">The cluster of yellow spots on the upper surface of leaves, which may
        also appear chlorotic.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_spider_mite_2">This gives the leaf a specked or mottled appearance, attacked leaves
        turn bronze, or rusty, purple or yellow brown color, spider’s mites and webbing are present on the lower leaf
        surface, which may appear tan or yellow and have a crusty texture.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_spider_mite">Spider mite outbreaks are prevalent in hot, dry circumstances,
        particularly on drought-stressed corn. Feeding by spider mites lowers the photosynthetic capacities of the leaf
        and can eventually destroy it. Proper irrigation to avoid drought stress, as well as the removal of alternate
        grass hosts, are all part of the prevention strategy. Miticides, when used when economic thresholds are reached,
        can aid in the control of infestations and the protection of yield potential.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_spider_mite" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_target_spot">The fungus Corynespora cassiicola causes the disease. Target spot is
        frequently misdiagnosed in its early stages because the symptoms are difficult to distinguish and can be
        confused with bacterial spot and early blight.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_1">The disease starts on the older leaves and spreads upwards.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_2">The first signs are irregular-shaped spots with a yellow margin.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_3">Spread to all leaflets and to other leaves is rapid, causing the leaves
        to turn yellow, collapse and die.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_4">Spots also occur on the stems. They are long and thin. Small light
        brown spots with dark margins may also occur on the fruit.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_target_spot">Do not plant new crops next to older ones that have the disease. Check
        all seedlings in the nursery, and throw away any with leaf spots. Remove a few branches from the lower part of
        the plants to allow better airflow at the base. Remove and burn the lower leaves as soon as the disease is seen,
        especially after the lower fruit trusses have been picked. Keep plots free from weeds, as some may be hosts of
        the fungus. Do not use overhead irrigation; otherwise, it will create conditions for spore production and
        infection. Collect and burn as much of the crop as possible when the harvest is complete. Practice crop
        rotation, leaving 3 years before replanting tomato on the same land.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_target_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>


    <string name="crop_id_banana" translatable="false">Banana</string>
    <string name="crop_id_coffee" translatable="false">Coffee</string>
    <string name="crop_id_rice" translatable="false">Rice</string>

    <string name="crop_name_banana">Banana</string>
    <string name="crop_name_coffee">Coffee</string>
    <string name="crop_name_rice">Rice</string>

    <string name="crop_sci_name_banana" translatable="false">Musa</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_coffee" translatable="false">Coffea</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_rice" translatable="false">Oryza Sativa</string>

    <string name="crop_desc_banana">Banana, locally known as “Saging” fruit of the genus Musa, of the family Musaceae,
        one of the most important fruit crops of the world. The banana is grown in the topic, and, though it is most
        widely consumed in those regions, it is valued worldwide for its flavour, nutritional value, and availability
        throughout the year. Cavendish, or desert, banana is most commonly eaten fresh thought they may be fried or
        mashed and chilled in pies or puddings. They may also be used to flavour muffins, cakes, or breads. Cooking
        varieties, or plantains, are starchy rather than sweet and are grow extensively as a staple food source in
        tropical regions; they are cooked when ripe or immature. A ripe fruit contains as much as 22 percent of
        carbohydrate and is high in dietary fiber, potassium, manganese, and vitamins B6 and C.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_coffee">The coffee beans (Coffea) locally known as “Kape” you pour into your grinder every
        morning are the roasted seeds of the coffee plant. Coffee plants are flowering shrubs that produce berries.
        Though they’re called cherries, these fruits aren’t related to the kind of cherry you might put in a pie. When
        these cherries ripen, coffee growers pick them and process them, removing the fruit and letting the green coffee
        beans inside dry out. Before they get to you, a roaster typically buys those green coffee beans and roasts them.
        Now they’re the aromatic brown bean you recognize!
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_rice">Rice, (Oryza sativa) locally known as “Palay” edible starchy cereal grain and the
        grass plant (family Poaceae) by which it is produced. Roughly one-half of the world population, including
        virtually all of East and Southeast Asia, is wholly dependent upon rice as a staple food; 95 percent of the
        world’s rice crop is eaten by humans. Rice is cooked by boiling, or it can be ground into a flour. It is eaten
        alone and in a great variety of soups, side dishes, and main dishes in Asian, Middle Eastern, and many other
        cuisines. Other products in which rice used are breakfast cereals, noodles, and such alcoholic beverage as
        Japanese sake.
    </string>
    <string name="ui_text_diagnosable">Diagnosable</string>
    <string name="ui_text_detectable">Detectable</string>


</resources>