<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <!-- Application name -->
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">CropSpot</string>

    <!-- App Text   -->
    <string name="ui_text_login">Login</string>
    <string name="ui_text_register">Register</string>
    <string name="ui_text_logout">Logout</string>
    <string name="ui_text_main">Hi</string>
    <string name="ui_user_guest">Guest</string>

    <!-- BUTTON:title texts -->
    <string name="ui_text_camera" translatable="false">Camera</string>
    <string name="ui_text_gallery" translatable="false">Gallery</string>
    <string name="ui_text_cancel">Cancel</string>

    <!-- TITLE texts -->
    <string name="ui_head_account">Accounts</string>

    <!-- MENU_ITEM:title texts -->
    <string name="ui_text_search">Search</string>
    <string name="ui_text_account" translatable="false">Account</string>
    <string name="ui_text_settings" translatable="false">Settings</string>

    <!-- MENU_ITEM:contentDescription texts -->
    <string name="ui_desc_search">More crop disease information</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_account">Login or Register account</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_settings">Personalize the app</string>

    <!-- DESCRIPTION texts -->
    <string name="ui_desc_login">Login to carry over your diagnosis and search history across multiple devices.</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_register">Register an account to save and access your data on any device.</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_logout">Are you sure? Subsequent diagnosis and search queries will not be saved</string>

    <string name="ui_text_diseases">Diseases</string>
    <string name="ui_text_crops">Crops</string>
    <string name="ui_text_today">Today</string>
    <string name="ui_hint_search">Search diseases</string>

    <!-- InferenceDialog -->
    <string name="ui_text_result">Result</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_diagnosis_fail">Unable to diagnose</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_diagnosis_fail">No %s detected</string>
    <string name="ui_text_analyzing">Analyzing…</string>
    <string name="ui_head_search">Showing results for</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_search">No results found</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_history">No diagnosis found</string>

    <!-- Settings -->
    <string name="ui_head_customization">Customization</string>
    <string name="ui_text_theme" translatable="false">Theme</string>
    <string name="ui_text_language">Language</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_lang">Choose Language</string>
    <string name="ui_head_personal">Personal Data</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_diagnosis">Clear Diagnosis History</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_clear_diagnosis">Erase all of the recorded diagnosis of this account permanently</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_search">Clear Search History</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_clear_search">Erase all of the search queries made in this account permanently</string>
    <!-- SettingsDialog -->
    <string name="ui_warn_clear_diagnosis">Are you sure? All recorded diagnosis will be lost permanently</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_clear_search">Are you sure? All searched queries will be lost permanently</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_diagnosis_success">Diagnosis history cleared</string>
    <string name="ui_text_clear_search_success">Search history cleared</string>

    <string name="ui_text_symptoms">Symptoms</string>
    <string name="ui_text_treatment">Treatment</string>
    <string name="ui_text_cause">Cause</string>


    <string name="ui_desc_img_toolbar" translatable="false">Crop Image</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_img_disease" translatable="false">Disease Image</string>

    <string name="ui_hint_diagnose">Diagnose plant diseases with a leaf picture. Try to submit an image from your phone
        camera/gallery
    </string>


    <!-- Variables -->
    <string name="val_labels" translatable="false">labels.txt</string>
    <string name="var_dataset" translatable="false" tools:ignore="Typos">set1</string>
    <string name="var_dim" translatable="false">224</string>
    <string name="val_healthy" translatable="false">Healthy</string>
    <string name="val_activity_settings" translatable="false">SettingsActivity</string>

    <!-- Dataset -->
    <string name="val_vector_fungi" translatable="false">Fungi</string>
    <string name="val_vector_pest" translatable="false">Pest</string>
    <string name="val_vector_bacteria" translatable="false">Bacteria</string>

    <string name="disease_bacterial_spot" translatable="false">Bacterial Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_common_rust" translatable="false">Common Rust</string>
    <string name="disease_cercospora_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Cercospora Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_septoria_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Septoria Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_northern_leaf_blight" translatable="false">Northern Leaf Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_early_blight" translatable="false">Early Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_late_blight" translatable="false">Late Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_powdery_mildew" translatable="false">Powdery Mildew</string>
    <string name="disease_leaf_mold" translatable="false">Leaf Mold</string>
    <string name="disease_spider_mite" translatable="false">Spider Mite</string>
    <string name="disease_target_spot" translatable="false">Target Spot</string>

    <string name="crop_id_bell_pepper" translatable="false">Bell Pepper</string>
    <string name="crop_id_corn" translatable="false">Corn</string>
    <string name="crop_id_potato" translatable="false">Potato</string>
    <string name="crop_id_squash" translatable="false">Squash</string>
    <string name="crop_id_tomato" translatable="false">Tomato</string>
    <string name="crop_name_bell_pepper">Bell Pepper</string>
    <string name="crop_name_corn">Corn</string>
    <string name="crop_name_potato">Potato</string>
    <string name="crop_name_squash">Squash</string>
    <string name="crop_name_tomato">Tomato</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_bell_pepper" translatable="false">Capsicum anuum</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_corn" translatable="false">Zea mays</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_potato" translatable="false">Solanum tuberosum</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_squash" translatable="false">Cucurbita maxima</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_tomato" translatable="false">Solanum lycopersicum</string>

    <string name="crop_desc_bell_pepper">Bell peppers (Capsicum anuum) locally known as “Alsal”, is a member of the
        capsicum family, which includes mild peppers, have a mild, sweet flavor and crisp, juicy flesh. According to
        foodfacts.com, bell peppers do not have a significant level of spiciness when compared to other peppers. Red
        bell peppers, as well as some yellow and orange types, are sweeter. Pepper plant seedlings should always be
        started indoors. To germinate, the seeds require the warmth of your home. Fill a seed tray halfway with seed
        starting soil or well-draining potting soil, then fill each container with one to three seeds. Place the tray in
        a warm location or use a warming pad to keep it between 70- and 90-degrees Fahrenheit. (21-32 C.) – the warmer
        the better. They are high in vitamin A, vitamin C, and potassium. Bell peppers also provide a good source of
        fiber, folate, and iron. Bell peppers, in addition to being high in nutrients, provide a pleasant and
        low-calorie crunch with every bite.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_corn">Corn (Zea mays) locally known as “Mais” is a large grain plant came from the grass
        family and a native to Central America, but it is now cultivated all around the world. It has six major types
        including popcorn, flour corn, dent corn, sweet corn, pod corn, and flint corn. This popular cereal grain has
        numerous purposes, but it is mostly used for culinary purposes. It is usually eaten boiled, grilled, and
        ingredients in cooking some of our favorite dishes. It has been also used to make corn flour, cornmeal, corn
        oil, corn syrup, tortilla chips, and other corn processed products. It contains dietary fiber, calories,
        carbohydrates, proteins, omega-3 fatty acids, and other nutrients. It has vitamins A, B, E, pantothenic acid,
        riboflavin, niacin, folate, and thiamine. It has minerals such as copper, potassium, iron, phosphorus, zinc,
        manganese, calcium, and magnesium. Corn plants are tall, therefore if placed on the north side, they will not
        cast shadows on other garden plants, reducing plant productivity. The ideal temperature range is 60 to 85
        degrees Fahrenheit. Temperatures below 50 degrees F. Corn is not going to grow. Plants should be spaced 8 to 10
        inches apart. Plant hills 2 to 3 feet apart with 3 to 4 plants per hill as an alternative configuration.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_potato">Potato (Solanum tuberosum L.) locally known as “patatas“, is a root vegetable native
        to the Americas, with the plant itself being a perennial in the nightshade family Solanaceae. It includes high
        levels of vitamin B-complex as well as vitamin C. A potato has more vitamin C than other fruits. Potatoes also
        contain a variety of minerals, including potassium, magnesium, phosphorus, iron, and calcium. Every mineral has
        its own function in keeping the body healthy. Potatoes are also high in fiber, which gives you a sensation of
        fullness and aids digestion. When potatoes are cooked with their skins on, they retain the majority of their
        fiber. Potato can reach a height of 100 cm (40 inches). As the potato plant matures, its compound leaves produce
        starch, which is then transmitted to the tips of its underground stems. The stems thicken to develop a few or up
        to 20 tubers near the soil surface.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_squash">Squash (Cucurbita maxima), locally known as “kalabasa”, is an annual herbaceous vine
        that can grow to be four meters long or more. It has a huge fruit with a yellow, meaty inside and is a popular
        vegetable in Filipino recipes like ginataang kalabasa and pinakbet. It is high in vitamin A, which is beneficial
        for maintaining eye health, boosting the immune system, and supporting cell growth among others. When producing
        squash, it is crucial to know that this food develops best in soils rich in organic material, according to the
        Agricultural Training Institute in the Cordillera Administrative Region (ATI-CAR). It is also fruitful all year,
        especially in areas with temperatures ranging from 18 to 30 degrees Celsius.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_tomato">Tomato (Solanum lycopersicum), locally known as “Kamatis“, is a savory, often red,
        edible fruit that grows on a plant. Tomato fruit is consumed in a variety of ways, including raw, as a component
        in numerous meals and sauces, and in beverages. While it is botanically a fruit, it is regarded as a vegetable
        in the culinary world, which has caused some confusion. The tomato is a member of the nightshade family. The
        plants normally develop to a height of 1–3 meters (3–10 ft) and have a weak, woody stem that vines over adjacent
        plants. It is a perennial, although often grown outdoors in temperate climates as an annual. Tomatoes are a top
        source of vitamins A and C. It also has a lot of fiber, beta-carotene, iron, lycopene, magnesium, niacin,
        potassium, phosphorus, riboflavin, and thiamine. Tomatoes have low levels of saturated fat, cholesterol, and
        salt. Moreover, unlike other foods, tomato cooking or processing (tomato paste, catsup, tomato soup, tomato
        sauce) is favorable to health. When tomatoes are heated, their cell walls break down, releasing more lycopene, a
        phytochemical that is beneficial to our health.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_cause_bacterial_spot">The bacterium Xanthomonas campestris py.vescatoria causes bacteria leaf spot. It thrives in areas with hot summers and frequent rainfall.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_spot_1">Once the symptoms of bacterial leaf spot begin to appear on your
        pepper plants, it’s too late to save them. However, if you take precautions before planting next season, you’ll
        have a better chance of preventing peppery leaf spot problems in the future. Crop rotation can help prevent
        bacterial leaf spot. Do not plant peppers or tomatoes in a location where either of these crops has been grown
        in the past four or five years. At the end of the season, remove all crop debris from the garden and destroy it.
        Do not compost plant debris that may contain the disease. Once the area is clean of all visible debris, till the
        soil or turn it with a shovel to bury any remaining bacteria. The bacterium is spread by splattering damp soil
        onto the leaves. Reduce the splatter by using a soaker hose and avoiding overhead watering. Stay out of the
        garden on wet days to avoid spreading disease on your hands and clothes. Bacterial leaf spot is also spread
        through infected seeds. Buy certified disease-free seeds and seedlings. It’s best not to save your own seeds if
        you’ve ever had a problem with bacterial leaf spot on peppers.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_spot_1">These lesions normally begin on the lower leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_cercospora_leaf_spot">Causes severe yield loss in cowpea.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_cercospora_leaf_spot_1">Use resistant varieties, If available. Disinfect tools used
        in
        an infested field. Crop rotation with rice and corn for at least 3-5 years may help reduce inoculum in the soil.
        Use resistant/moderately verities, if available.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_1">Leaves and fruit can be affected particularly in hot humid
        conditions.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_2">Leaf spots begin as small, round , brown, lesions and often
        with white/light brown center.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_3">Some spots are surrounded by a distinct yellow halo.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_cercospora_leaf_spot_4">Under the warm and wet condition, the lesions expand and the
        leaves may appear blighted.
    </string>

    <string name="disease_vector_bacterial_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_bacteria</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_cercospora_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_common_rust">Common rust is caused by the fungus Puccinia sorghi and occurs every
        growing season. It is seldom a concern in hybrid corn.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_common_rust_1">The disease by the development of dark, reddish-brown pustules
        (uredinia) scattered over both the upper and lower surfaces of the corn leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_common_rust_2">These pustules may appear on any above ground part of the plant, but
        are most abundant on the leaves. Pustules appear oval to elongate in shape, are generally small, less than 1/4
        inch long, and are surrounded by the leaf epidermal layer, where it has broken through.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_common_rust_3">If infections occur while the leaves are still in the whorl, these
        pustules may develop in bands across the surface as the leaf expands in size.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_common_rust_1">Plant resistant varieties(if available). Plow in old crops as soon as
        harvesting and ensure all crop is decomposed before panting.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_cause_early_blight">The diseases are caused by the fungus Alternaria solani.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_early_blight_1">Dark spots with concentric growth and yellow halos on leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_early_blight_2">Leaves dry out and fall, fruits may start to rot and eventually
        drop.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_early_blight_1" formatted="false">Use pathogen-free seed, or collect seed only from
        disease-free
        plants.
        Rotate out of tomatoes and related crops for at least two years. Control susceptible weeds such as black
        nightshade and hairy nightshade, and volunteer tomato plants throughout the rotation. Fertilize properly to
        maintain vigorous plant growth. Particularly, do not over-fertilize with potassium and maintain adequate levels
        of both nitrogen and phosphorus. Avoid working in plants when they are wet from rain, irrigation, or dew. Use
        drip irrigation instead of overhead irrigation to keep foliage dry. Stake the plants to increase airflow around
        the plant and facilitate drying. Staking will also reduce contact between the leaves and spore-contaminated
        soil. Apply plastic or organic mulch to reduce humidity and provide a barrier between contaminated soil and
        leaves. In the fall, remove or bury infected plants to reduce the likelihood of the pathogen surviving to the
        following year. For greenhouse production, early blight has been reduced by as much as 50% by covering houses
        with UV-absorbing vinyl film.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_common_rust" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_early_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_late_blight">Late blight is caused by the oomycete Phytophthora infestans. Oomycetes are
        fungus-like organisms also called water molds, but they are not true fungi. There are many different strains of
        P. infestans. Many clonal lineages affect both tomato and potato, but some lineages are specific to one host or
        the other.The host range is typically limited to potato and tomato, but hairy nightshade (Solanum physalifolium)
        is a closely related weed that can readily become infected and may contribute to disease spread. Under ideal
        conditions, such as a greenhouse, petunia also may become infected.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_late_blight_1">Dark brown spots on leaf tips, Spots turn into transparent wounds.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_late_blight_2">White fungus covers the underside of leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_late_blight_3">Leaves wilt and die off, Grayish-blue spots on potato tubers.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_late_blight_1">Avoid overhead irrigation/watering and overwatering of transplants.
        The
        bacterial speck and spot pathogens can be spread easily in the greenhouse when plant density is high and plant
        are watered overhead. Minimize overwatering transplant in the greenhouse and overhead watering when possible.
        Avoiding excessive handling of transplants. Bacteria can easily be spread on tools and on worker’s hands. Avoid
        handing transplant more than necessary, especially when wet. Choose, prepare, and maintain an appropriate field
        for planting tomatoes in soil that drains well. Remove voluntary tomatoes and from the fields before planting
        and during crop rotation years when non-host crops are planted.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_late_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_leaf_mold">The fungus passalora fulva causes leaf mold.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_1">Starts as pale green to yellowish spot-on upper leaf surfaces that turn a
        bright yellow.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_2">The spots merge as the disease progresses and the foliage then dies.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_3">Infected leaves curl, wither, and often drop from the plant. Flowers,
        stems, and fruit that maybe infected, although usually only leaf tissue is infected.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mold_4">When the disease does manifest on the fruit, tomatoes with leaf mold
        become dark in color, leathery, and root and stem end.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mold_1">Although infected seed is frequently the primary source of the disease,
        it can also be found in diseased plant waste or in the soil. Rain and wind spread the disease, as do tools and
        clothing, as well as insect activity. High relative humidity (more than 85%) paired with high temperatures
        promotes disease spread. Keeping this in mind, if you\'re growing tomatoes in a greenhouse, keep the night
        temperatures higher than the outside temperatures. Use only certified disease-free or treated seed when sowing.
        After harvest, remove and discard any crop trash. Between crop seasons, sanitize the greenhouse. To reduce leaf
        moisture, use fans and prevent overhead watering. Plants should also be staked and pruned to improve
        ventilation. If the disease is detected, use a fungicide as directed by the manufacturer at the first sign of
        infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_leaf_mold" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_northern_leaf_blight">It is causes by another fungus that overwinters in infested crop
        debris. The tan lesions can be small to very large and elliptical in shape, usually with smooth round ends.
        Mature lesions in humid conditions may appear duty in the middle as the fungus produces spores that are spread
        to the other leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_northern_leaf_blight_1">In a susceptible hybrid is one to sixth inches long
        cigar-shaped.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_northern_leaf_blight_2">The first appear as small light green to grayish spots
        approximately 1-2 weeks after infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_northern_leaf_blight_3">As the disease develops, the lesions spread to all leafy
        structures, including the husks, and produce dark spores, giving lesions as dirty appearance.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_northern_leaf_blight_1">Control of this disease is often focused on management and
        prevention. First, choose corn varieties or hybrids that are resistant or at least have moderate resistance to
        northern corn leaf blight. When you grow corn, make sure it does not stay wet for long periods of time. The
        fungus that causes this infection needs between six and 18 hours of leaf wetness to develop. Plant corn with
        enough space for airflow and water in the morning so leaves can dry throughout the day. The fungus overwinters
        in plant material, so it is also important to manage infected plants. Tilling the corn into the soil is one
        strategy, but with a small garden it may make more sense to just remove and destroy the affected plants.
        Treating northern corn leaf blight involves using fungicides. For most home gardeners this step isn’t needed,
        but if you have a bad infection, you may want to try this chemical treatment. The infection usually begins
        around the time of silking, and this is when the fungicide should be applied.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_northern_leaf_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_powdery_mildew">It causes several different species of fungus. Each species has its own
        preferred host plants. The species od powdery mildew that affects squash foliage (Erysiphe cichacearum) is
        different from those that target peas (Erysiphe pisi). Interestingly, this fungus lives on the outside of the
        leaves and does not penetrate the internal tissue. It can only grow on the surface of the leaf.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_powdery_mildew_1">The symptoms are the small, white, dusty spots on the young leaves
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_powdery_mildew_2">Initially, there will only be a few spots, but it spreads quickly,
        eventually covering the entire leaf surface.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_powdery_mildew_3">Powdery mildew is most commonly seen on the top of the leaves, but
        it can also appear on the leaf undersides, the stem, and even on the fruits.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_powdery_mildew_1">Don’t touch infected leaves and then touch the healthy leaves.
        You’ve just spread spores. Always plant squash in the full sun. shady conditions are more humid and that
        encourage spore germination. Cut off any leaves that show early signs of infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_powdery_mildew" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_septoria_leaf_spot">Causes of fungus: Septoria lycospersici can destroy tomato foliage
        and reduce yield. Through fruit infection is uncommon, the destruction of foliage can lead to fruit failure or
        make fruit prone to sunscald.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_septoria_leaf_spot_1">It develop on the calyx, leaves, and stems round lesions with
        dark margins and tan gray center develop on leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_septoria_leaf_spot_2">Black fruiting bodies(pycnidia) develop in center of lesions
        approximately 2 weeks after infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_septoria_leaf_spot_3">A thin, yellow halo often develops around lesions on leaflets.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_septoria_leaf_spot_1">Crops rotation, weed management, cultural practices,
        sanitation,
        fungicides
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_septoria_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_spider_mite">Spider mite feeding can cause numerous yellow or white tiny granulated
        spots on tomato leaves. The infestation mostly occurs under hot and dry conditions
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_spider_mite_1">The cluster of yellow spots on the upper surface of leaves, which may
        also appear chlorotic.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_spider_mite_2">This gives the leaf a specked or mottled appearance, attacked leaves
        turn bronze, or rusty, purple or yellow brown color, spider’s mites and webbing are present on the lower leaf
        surface, which may appear tan or yellow and have a crusty texture.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_spider_mite_1">Spider mite outbreaks are prevalent in hot, dry circumstances,
        particularly on drought-stressed corn. Feeding by spider mites lowers the photosynthetic capacities of the leaf
        and can eventually destroy it. Proper irrigation to avoid drought stress, as well as the removal of alternate
        grass hosts, are all part of the prevention strategy. Miticides, when used when economic thresholds are reached,
        can aid in the control of infestations and the protection of yield potential.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_spider_mite" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_target_spot">The fungus Corynespora cassiicola causes the disease. Target spot is
        frequently misdiagnosed in its early stages because the symptoms are difficult to distinguish and can be
        confused with bacterial spot and early blight.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_1">The disease starts on the older leaves and spreads upwards.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_2">The first signs are irregular-shaped spots with a yellow margin.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_3">Spread to all leaflets and to other leaves is rapid, causing the leaves
        to turn yellow, collapse and die.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_target_spot_4">Spots also occur on the stems. They are long and thin. Small light
        brown spots with dark margins may also occur on the fruit.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_target_spot_1">Do not plant new crops next to older ones that have the disease.
        Check
        all seedlings in the nursery, and throw away any with leaf spots. Remove a few branches from the lower part of
        the plants to allow better airflow at the base. Remove and burn the lower leaves as soon as the disease is seen,
        especially after the lower fruit trusses have been picked. Keep plots free from weeds, as some may be hosts of
        the fungus. Do not use overhead irrigation; otherwise, it will create conditions for spore production and
        infection. Collect and burn as much of the crop as possible when the harvest is complete. Practice crop
        rotation, leaving 3 years before replanting tomato on the same land.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_target_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>


    <string name="crop_id_banana" translatable="false">Banana</string>
    <string name="crop_id_coffee" translatable="false">Coffee</string>
    <string name="crop_id_rice" translatable="false">Rice</string>

    <string name="crop_name_banana">Banana</string>
    <string name="crop_name_coffee">Coffee</string>
    <string name="crop_name_rice">Rice</string>

    <string name="crop_sci_name_banana" translatable="false">Musa</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_coffee" translatable="false">Coffea</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_rice" translatable="false">Oryza Sativa</string>

    <string name="crop_desc_banana">Banana, locally known as “Saging” fruit of the genus Musa, of the family Musaceae,
        one of the most important fruit crops of the world. The banana is grown in the topic, and, though it is most
        widely consumed in those regions, it is valued worldwide for its flavour, nutritional value, and availability
        throughout the year. Cavendish, or desert, banana is most commonly eaten fresh thought they may be fried or
        mashed and chilled in pies or puddings. They may also be used to flavour muffins, cakes, or breads. Cooking
        varieties, or plantains, are starchy rather than sweet and are grow extensively as a staple food source in
        tropical regions; they are cooked when ripe or immature. A ripe fruit contains as much as 22 percent of
        carbohydrate and is high in dietary fiber, potassium, manganese, and vitamins B6 and C.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_coffee">The coffee beans (Coffea) locally known as “kape” you pour into your grinder every
        morning are the roasted seeds of the coffee plant. Coffee plants are flowering shrubs that produce berries.
        Though they’re called cherries, these fruits aren’t related to the kind of cherry you might put in a pie. When
        these cherries ripen, coffee growers pick them and process them, removing the fruit and letting the green coffee
        beans inside dry out. Before they get to you, a roaster typically buys those green coffee beans and roasts them.
        Now they’re the aromatic brown bean you recognize!
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_rice">Rice, (Oryza sativa) locally known as “palay” edible starchy cereal grain and the
        grass plant (family Poaceae) by which it is produced. Roughly one-half of the world population, including
        virtually all of East and Southeast Asia, is wholly dependent upon rice as a staple food; 95 percent of the
        world’s rice crop is eaten by humans. Rice is cooked by boiling, or it can be ground into a flour. It is eaten
        alone and in a great variety of soups, side dishes, and main dishes in Asian, Middle Eastern, and many other
        cuisines. Other products in which rice used are breakfast cereals, noodles, and such alcoholic beverage as
        Japanese sake.
    </string>
    <string name="ui_text_diagnosable">Diagnosable</string>
    <string name="ui_text_detectable">Detectable</string>
    <string name="ui_head_diagnosis_history">Diagnosis History</string>

    <string name="crop_id_bitter_gourd" translatable="false">Bitter Gourd</string>
    <string name="crop_id_cabbage" translatable="false">Cabbage</string>
    <string name="crop_id_cassava" translatable="false">Cassava</string>
    <string name="crop_id_eggplant" translatable="false">Eggplant</string>
    <string name="crop_id_mango" translatable="false">Mango</string>
    <string name="crop_id_okra" translatable="false">Okra</string>
    <string name="crop_id_pineapple" translatable="false">Pineapple</string>
    <string name="crop_id_string_beans" translatable="false">String Beans</string>

    <string name="crop_name_bitter_gourd">Bitter Gourd</string>
    <string name="crop_name_cabbage">Cabbage</string>
    <string name="crop_name_cassava">Cassava</string>
    <string name="crop_name_eggplant">Eggplant</string>
    <string name="crop_name_mango">Mango</string>
    <string name="crop_name_okra">Okra</string>
    <string name="crop_name_pineapple">Pineapple</string>
    <string name="crop_name_string_beans">String Beans</string>

    <string name="crop_sci_name_bitter_gourd" translatable="false">Momordica charantia</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_cabbage" translatable="false">Brassica oleracea</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_cassava" translatable="false">Manohit esculenta</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_eggplant" translatable="false">Solanum melongena</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_mango" translatable="false">Mangifera indica</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_okra" translatable="false">Abelmoschus esculentus</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_pineapple" translatable="false">Ananas comosus</string>
    <string name="crop_sci_name_string_beans" translatable="false">Phaseolus vulgaris</string>
    <string name="crop_desc_bitter_gourd">Bitter gourd (Momordica charantia) is a green-skinned vegetable with white to
        translucent flesh and a taste that fits its name. Unless you grew up with bitter gourd as part of your regular
        diet, it might take you a while to warm up to the bitter flavor. Bitter gourd is also a vegetable of many names.
        It is equally known as bitter melon, bitter cucumber, balsam-pear, bitter apple, or bitter squash. This
        vegetable is also called karela in India, nigauri in Japan, goya in Okinawa, ampalaya in the Philippines, and
        ku-gua throughout China. Momordica charantia likely originated in eastern India or southern China. It favors hot
        and humid climates with plenty of sunshine and regular water access. Today, you can find bitter gourd growing in
        fields across Asia, though it has also become popular in the Caribbean and South America. There are several
        varieties of bitter gourd, but the two most common are Chinese bitter gourd and Indian bitter gourd. The Chinese
        variety more closely resembles a pale green cucumber with crimped, bumpy skin. The Indian variety has narrow,
        tapered ends and sharp, angled ridges all over its surface. The differences between these varieties are mostly
        visual, and both offer similar flavor and health benefits.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_cabbage">Cabbage(Brassica oleracea), locally known as “Repolyo” vegetable and fodder plant
        of the mustard family (Brassicaceae), the various agricultural forms of which have been developed by long
        cultivation from the wild cabbage (Brassica oleracea). The edible portions of all cabbage forms—which include
        kale, broccoli, and Brussels sprouts—are low in calories and are an excellent source of vitamin C. Head cabbage,
        generally designated simply “cabbage,” is a major table vegetable in most countries of the temperate zone. All
        forms of cabbage have succulent leaves that are free of hairs and covered with a waxy coating, which often gives
        the leaf surface a gray-green or blue-green colour. The plants grow best in mild to cool climates and tolerate
        frost; some forms tolerate hard freezing at certain periods of growth. Hot weather impairs growth and quality.
        The common forms of cabbage may be classified according to the plant parts used for food.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_cassava">Cassava (Manohit esculenta) locally known as “kamoteng kahoy”, is a root vegetable.
        People use the root as a food and to make medicine. Cassava is used for tiredness, dehydration in people with
        diarrhea, sepsis, and to induce labor, but there is no good scientific evidence to support these uses. Cassava
        root and leaves are eaten as food. The nutritional value of cassava is similar to a potato. However, cassava
        contains chemicals called cyanogenic glycosides. These chemicals can release cyanide in the body. Cassava must
        be prepared correctly before eating to prevent cyanide poisoning.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_eggplant">Eggplant (Solanom melongena) locally known as “Talong” also called aubergine or
        Guinea squash, tender perennial plant of the nightshade family (Solanaceae), grown for its edible fruits.
        Eggplant requires a warm climate and has been cultivated in its, native Southeast Asia since remote antiquity. A
        staple in cuisines of the Mediterranean region, eggplant figures prominently in such classic dishes as a Greek
        moussaka, the Italian eggplant parmigiana, and the Middle Eastern relish baba ghanoush. It is also frequently
        served as a baked, grilled, friend, or boiled vegetable and is used as a garnish and in strew.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_mango">Mango, (Mangifera indica), For centuries, these tropical tree fruits have been
        enjoyed for their sweet, bright flavor. More recently, research has uncovered added benefits in the form of key
        nutrients that help people fight disease, maintain a healthy weight, and even ward off some signs of aging. Like
        peaches and cherries, mangoes are known as a stone fruit because of their center pit, which is easily
        recognizable because of its large size and flattened oval shape. Mangoes are originally from India but now grow
        abundantly in Mexico, South America, and parts of Florida and California. While at one time considered exotic,
        mango fruit is now available in most supermarkets and is a common ingredient in many dishes, owing to its
        popular flavor and versatility — it\'s delicious sliced, chopped, pureed, juiced, and even roasted. Here is
        everything you need to know about mangoes, including their nutrition content and health benefits, plus more ways
        to enjoy eating them.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_okra">Lady’s fingers (Abelmoschus esculentus) locally known as “Okra” are a type of green
        vegetable, long fingers like, having a small tip at the taping end. Its head shows a bulge, lighter green in
        shade, which is often removed as inedible portion. The cross section cut okra shows white colored round seeds
        spread entirely inside the vegetable. One of the peculiar signs of this is the internal stickiness. The lady’s
        finger may be cut in to round pieces or sliced in to 4 halfes or may be put whole in to round mix vegetable
        subji. The taste is very specific to the vegetable and generally liked by children.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_pineapple">Pineapple (Ananas comosus) locally known as “Pinya“. Native to South America, it
        was named for its resemblance to a pine cone. Christopher Columbus is credited with discovering the pineapple on
        the island of Guadeloupe in 1493. Today, Hawaii produces only ten percent of the world\'s pineapple crops. Other
        countries contributing to the pineapple industry include Mexico, Honduras, Dominican Republic, Philippines,
        Thailand, Costa Rica, and China. The pineapple plant is low-growing with spiky leaves protruding from the
        ground. The leaves are the same shape as the greenery on the top of the fruit, which grows on a central stem
        from the plant. It takes about two years for the plant to produce a single pineapple fruit with its bright
        yellow, fibrous flesh and skin covered with vibrant “eyes.“ Pineapple is common in supermarkets, easy to cut up,
        and, considering how much fruit you get, relatively inexpensive.
    </string>
    <string name="crop_desc_string_beans">String beans (Phaseolus vulgaris) locally known as “Sitao” is one of the most
        widely grown vegetables in the Philippines. It is a true legume and botanically more closely related to cowpea.
        The tender pods are edible while the skin is still smooth and before seeds mature or expand. The young leaves
        and stem can be boiled or steamed and eaten as green vegetables. Per 100 grams of fresh weight, the green pods
        can provide 2 grams protein, 8.2 grams carbohydrates, and substantial amount of calcium and other minerals. When
        boiled, the young leaves are a good source of protein and vitamin A. It is grown throughout the year but the
        best time to plant is from May to June for wet season planting and from October to November for dry season.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_algal_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Algal Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_anthracnose" translatable="false">Anthracnose</string>
    <string name="disease_aphids" translatable="false">Aphids</string>
    <string name="disease_bacterial_blight" translatable="false">Bacterial Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_bacterial_leaf_streak" translatable="false">Bacterial Leaf Streak</string>
    <string name="disease_banana_freckle" translatable="false">Banana Freckle</string>
    <string name="disease_banana_streak" translatable="false">Banana Streak</string>
    <string name="disease_black_rot" translatable="false">Black Rot</string>
    <string name="disease_blast" translatable="false">Blast</string>
    <string name="disease_brown_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Brown Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_downy_mildew" translatable="false">Downy Mildew</string>
    <string name="disease_lace_wing" translatable="false">Lace Wing</string>
    <string name="disease_leaf_miner" translatable="false">Leaf Miner</string>
    <string name="disease_leaf_mosaic" translatable="false">Leaf Mosaic</string>
    <string name="disease_mealybug_wilt" translatable="false">Mealybug Wilt</string>
    <string name="disease_pineapple_heart_rot" translatable="false">Pineapple Heart Rot</string>
    <string name="disease_rust_thrips" translatable="false">Rust Thrips</string>
    <string name="disease_sigatoka_leaf_spot" translatable="false">Sigatoka Leaf Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_sooty_mold" translatable="false">Sooty Mold</string>
    <string name="disease_southern_blight" translatable="false">Southern Blight</string>
    <string name="disease_tobacco_caterpillar" translatable="false">Tobacco Caterpillar</string>
    <string name="disease_tungro" translatable="false">Tungro</string>
    <string name="disease_yellow_spot" translatable="false">Yellow Spot</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_algal_leaf_spot">Algal leaf spot is a foliar disease most commonly seen in warm humid
        climates or in greenhouses. The causal organism is Cephaleuros virescens, a green parasitic alga whose usual
        hosts are plants with leathery leaves such as cotoneasters, magnolias, hollies, rhododendrons and viburnums.
        Algal leaf spot is sometimes called green scurf because the spots may have a crusty, fuzzy or flaky appearance.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_algal_leaf_spot_1">Characterized by grayish, green, brown or orange cushion-like
        blotches on the leaf surface.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_algal_leaf_spot_2">Some hosts may also have diseased twigs and branches that are
        girdled and stunted with reddish brown fruiting bodies.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_algal_leaf_spot_3">The spots are generally 1/2 inch or less in diameter although they
        may coalesce to form larger colonies. Leaf tissue may die beneath the spots and the leaves may yellow and drop
        prematurely.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_algal_leaf_spot_1">Algal leaf spot is not usually a serious problem. When the
        disease is mild, remove and destroy leaves with spots as well as diseased branches. Also, rake up and destroy
        affected leaves that have fallen to the ground.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_algal_leaf_spot_2">Since algal leaf spot is most often a problem for plants that are
        under stress, an important step in management is to improve growing conditions.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_algal_leaf_spot_3">Make sure that plants are receiving the recommended amounts of
        sunlight, water, and fertilizer. If needed, improve air circulation around affected plants by removing or
        thinning out nearby vegetation.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_algal_leaf_spot_4">Avoid overhead irrigation whenever possible. When algal leaf spot
        is severe, copper fungicide sprays are recommended.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_algal_leaf_spot_5">Sprays may need to be applied every 2 weeks if wet conditions
        persist. However, when the affected plant is too tall to apply sprays safely, treatment may not be feasible for
        the homeowner and may require professional assistance.
    </string>
    <string name="val_vector_algae" translatable="false">Algae</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_algal_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_algae</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_anthracnose">Mango anthracnose is caused by the fungus Colletotrichum gloeosporioides
        var minor (also known by the name of its perfect stage Glomerella cingulata var minor). Spore production by this
        fungus is favoured by wet or humid weather. The dispersal of these spores is particularly favoured by rain and
        wind. This enables spread of the disease over relatively short distances. In areas where rain is prevalent
        during flowering and fruit set, anthracnose can cause destruction of the inflorescences and infection and drop
        of young fruit. This can obviously lead to serious losses.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_anthracnose_1">On leaves, spots form commonly towards the margins. They are tan to
        dark brown in colour, often with a darker border. Infection of young leaf flushes may occur when their emergence
        coincides with rainy weather. These infections often show up as lesions along the margins of the young bronze or
        pale green leaves, in which case they are semi-circular in shape.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_anthracnose_2">In very humid weather new twigs may show a dark affected area from the
        tip backwards, sometimes with defoliation of the young shoots.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_anthracnose_3">When newly formed fruit are affected the anthracnose shows as large,
        sunken, black lesions and the fruits so affected drop off. Medium to large green immature fruit affected with
        pre-harvest anthracnose show large lesions which are glossy, black and sunken. With this fruit, splits and
        oozing often occurs.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_anthracnose_4">The most common fruit anthracnose results from latent infections (see
        above) and is seen as slightly depressed grey-black areas in the skin on ripening fruit. In time the typical
        pink to orange spore masses (acervuli) form on this tissue.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_anthracnose_1">Regular spraying of trees from flowering time onwards with mancozeb
        (at recommended label rates every 14 days) is useful to reduce the level of infection in the developing fruit.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_anthracnose_2">Do not use mancozeb within 14 days of harvest. If anthracnose becomes
        serious in green immature fruit it would be useful to give a couple of judicious sprays of prochloraz.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_anthracnose_3">It is important however not to overuse prochloraz as this may lead to
        development of resistant anthracnose strains.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_anthracnose_4">Copper sprays recommended for the control of mango scab will also
        control anthracnose with only a one day withholding period.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_anthracnose_5">Post-harvest treatments are available for control of anthracnose in
        mango fruit. Prochloraz is used as a cold nonrecirculating spray.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_anthracnose_6">Hot water dips used to control fruit flies will also control
        anthracnose and stem end rots. Hot benomyl dips will control anthracnose and are useful where stem end rots are
        a problem.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_anthracnose" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_aphids">The primary damage caused by aphids to eggplants is the production of sticky
        honeydew and subsequent growth of black sooty mold on the honeydew. They can also stunt plants by feeding on
        them early in the season before bloom. There do not appear to be any serious virus problems associated with
        aphid infestations.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_aphids_1">A spotting and chlorosis of leaves.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_aphids_2">Leaf curling and distortion and abscission of flowers.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_aphids_1">Winged aphids are repelled by silver- or aluminum-colored mulches. If
        there is a probability of severe virus pressure, place reflective polyethylene mulches on planting beds before
        seeding or transplanting to significantly reduce rate of colonization by winged aphids and delay the buildup of
        damaging numbers of aphids by 4- to 6-weeks.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_aphids_2">While this approach is mainly effective in delaying or reducing the
        incidence of virus diseases transmitted by winged aphids and whiteflies, reflective mulches can also delay the
        buildup of wingless aphids that arise as a result of colonization by winged individuals.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_aphids_3" formatted="false">The mulches lose their effectiveness when more than 60%
        of the surface is
        covered by foliage or if the mulch becomes fouled with dust or soil. Therefore, they are effective only for the
        first few weeks after transplanting.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_aphids" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_bacterial_blight">caused by Xanthomonas oryzae pv. Oryzae. The disease is most likely to
        develop in areas that have weeds and stubbles of infected plants. It can occur in both tropical and temperate
        environments, particularly in irrigated and rainfed lowland areas. In general, the disease favors temperatures
        at 25−34°C, with relative humidity above 70%. It is commonly observed when strong winds and continuous heavy
        rains occur, allowing the disease-causing bacteria to easily spread through ooze droplets on lesions of infected
        plants. Bacterial blight can be severe in susceptible rice varieties under high nitrogen fertilization.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_blight_1">Water-soaked to yellowish stripes on leaf blades or starting at
        leaf tips with a wavy margin
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_blight_2">Leaves with undulated yellowish white or golden yellow marginal
        necrosis, drying of leaves back from tip and curling, leaving mid rib intact are the major symptoms.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_blight_3">Appearance of bacterial ooze that looks like a milky or opaque
        dewdrop on young lesions early in the morning
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_blight_4">Severely infected leaves tend to dry quickly</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_blight_5">loss in grain yield may be up to 60%.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_1">Grow Tolerant varieties (IR 20 IR 72,PONMANI , TKM 6).</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_2">Secure disease free seed</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_3">Grow nurseries preferably in isolated upland conditions</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_4">Avoid clipping of seedlings during transplanting.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_5">Balanced fertilization, avoid excess N - application</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_6">Skip N - application at booting (if disease is moderate)
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_7">Drain the field (except at flowering stage of the crop)</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_8">Destruction of weeds and collateral hosts</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_9">Avoid flow of water from affected fields</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_blight_10">Maintain proper plant spacing</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_bacterial_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_bacteria</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_bacterial_leaf_streak">caused by Xanthomonas oryzae pv. oryzicola. Bacterial leaf streak
        occurs in areas with high temperature and high humidity. It is transmitted through seeds and infected stubbles
        to the next planting season. It can occur in fields where X. oryzae pv. oryzicola bacteria is present on leaves,
        in the water, or in the debris left after harvest.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_leaf_streak_1">Symptoms initially appear as small, water-soaked, linear
        lesions between leaf veins. These streaks are initially dark green and later become light brown to yellowish
        gray.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_leaf_streak_2">The lesions are translucent when held against the light.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_leaf_streak_3">Entire leaves may become brown and die when the disease is
        very severe.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_leaf_streak_4">Under humid conditions, yellow droplets of bacterial ooze,
        which contain masses of bacterial cells, may be observed on the surface of leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_bacterial_leaf_streak_5">Bacterial leaf streak may be confused with narrow brown
        spot.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_1">Plant resistant varieties.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_2">Treat seeds with hot water.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_3">Keep fields clean—remove weed hosts and plow under rice
        stubble, straw, rice ratoons, and volunteer seedlings, which may be infected by the bacteria.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_4">Use balanced amounts of plant nutrients, especially
        nitrogen.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_5">Ensure good drainage of fields (in conventionally flooded
        crops) and nurseries.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_6">Drain the field during severe flood.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_7">Dry the field during the fallow period to kill the bacteria
        in the soil and in plant residues.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_bacterial_leaf_streak_8">In cases of severe infection, when yield may be affected, a
        copper-based fungicide applied at heading can be effective in controlling the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_bacterial_leaf_streak" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_bacteria</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_banana_freckle">The symptoms are caused by the fungus Phyllosticta maculata. It can affect banana plants at all stages of the production cycle and is considered a ’wet spore’ organism in that its spores need water as a way of dispersal (raindrops, water splashes, dew droplets for example). Banana freckle may also be spread through the movement of infected plant material and fruits. The freckle spots contain the fungal structures that produce spores. As they germinate, the spores produce filaments that penetrate the host and multiply within and between cells, creating new spots or lesions in the superficial layers of the plant tissue. The incubation period can be as little as 20 days in hot humid weather.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_banana_freckle_1">The most characteristic symptoms are dark brown to black spots of
        different sizes on leaves and fruit. The surface of the leaf and the skin of the fruit feel like sandpaper. The
        small spots are less than 1mm in diameter. They may cluster in lines and appear as streaks running diagonally
        across the leaf, or from the midrib to the leaf edge, often along the veins. The larger spots are up to 4mm in
        diameter and can also appear as streaks. Sometimes the center of these larger spots are lighter in color. Spots
        may also form on petioles, midribs, transition leaves and bracts. Fruit can also be affected by freckle as early
        as 2-4 weeks after bunch emergence. Individual spots first appear as minute reddish-brown flecks surrounded by a
        halo of dark-green, water-soaked tissue.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_banana_freckle_1">Always consider an integrated approach with preventive measures
        and biological treatments if available. Spraying the leaves and fruit with maneb every 2 weeks or once a month
        throughout the year can remarkably reduce the spread of spores. Spraying fungicides such as folpet,
        chlorothalonil, mancozeb, triazoles, propiconazole and those of the family of the strobilurins, biweekly can
        also produce effective results against the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_banana_freckle_2">As the infected leaves are the primary source of spores, placing a
        bag over the bananas, once harvested, creates a barrier to prevent spores from spreading to the fruit. Neem oil
        applications (1500 ppm) @ 5ml with surf (1g) or sandovit (1ml) per liter of water can be used prophylacticly, at
        flowering stage of the crop and at first appearance.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_banana_freckle" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_banana_streak">The symptoms of the disease can vary widely, depending on the type and amount of virus involved, the plant variety and the environmental conditions. The most common symptom is the formation of even or broken yellow streaks that run from the leaf midrib to the margin. These streaks later turn brown or black and can be interrupted by yellow blotches or eye-shaped patterns. Necrosis starts to appear on the leaf, starting from the margin, and sometimes affecting midrib and petiole. Occasionally, the internal tissues of the stem are also affected by decay. The latter symptom is particularly visible under low temperature and short-day conditions. Not all leaves are affected but plant growth is usually stunted, while the size of the bunches and fruits is reduced. Symptom: The disease is caused by a complex of viruses. The nature of the symptoms is determined by the concentration of viral particles in plants. Temperatures, and weather patters in general, also influence the outcome of an infection. The virus is spread from tree to tree or between fields through several species of mealybugs (Pseudococcidae). Another means of long distance dissemination is the use of infected planting material or seeds. It is not soil-borne and unlikely to be transmitted via mechanical injuries to plants through during field work. It is a worldwide problem that affect banana and related species and that can adversely affect plant growth, fruit yield and quality. The virus is unlikely to be spread on cutting tools or by mechanical means.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_banana_streak_1">The disease is caused by a complex of viruses. The nature of the
        symptoms is determined by the concentration of viral particles in plants. Temperatures, and weather patters in
        general, also influence the outcome of an infection. The virus is spread from tree to tree or between fields
        through several species of mealybugs (Pseudococcidae). Another means of long distance dissemination is the use
        of infected planting material or seeds. It is not soil-borne and unlikely to be transmitted via mechanical
        injuries to plants through during field work. It is a worldwide problem that affect banana and related species
        and that can adversely affect plant growth, fruit yield and quality. The virus is unlikely to be spread on
        cutting tools or by mechanical means.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_banana_streak_1">Always consider an integrated approach with preventive measures
        together with biological treatments if available. There is no chemical treatment of viral diseases. The waxy
        protective coating of mealybugs makes them difficult to kill. Treatments with insecticides such as deltamethrin
        can be used to control mealybug populations.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_banana_streak_2">Bio-control agents such as parasitoid wasps, lacewings or hover
        flies and lady birds can be used to control populations of mealybugs. Light mineral oils or neem extracts
        sprayed on leaves are also effective when populations are small.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_banana_streak_3">Use virus-free planting material from certified sources</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_banana_streak_4">Infected plants should be cut down and destroyed</string>

    <string name="val_vector_virus" translatable="false">Virus</string>

    <string name="disease_vector_banana_streak" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_virus</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_black_rot">caused by Xanthomonas campestris pv. campestris is one of the most
        devastating diseases of cruciferous crops and can result in high losses of yield and quality. It occurs
        worldwide and infects all brassica species.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_black_rot_1">Can appear at any growth stage as yellow, V-shaped lesions that extend
        toward the base of the leaf resulting in wilt and necrosis.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_black_rot_2">Blackening of veins within lesions and adjacent areas is a diagnostic
        feature of this pathogen.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_black_rot_3">Symptoms of black rot can be similar to those of drought stress,
        overwatering, or excessive fertilizer application, so identification confirmation from a diagnostician is
        important.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_1">Select seed that has been certified as disease-free.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_2">Treat seed with hot water to eradicate the bacteria. Treat seed for 15-
        30 minutes at 50° C, dry, and test for germination. This process must be done carefully and it is recommended
        that a small sample of seed be tested for the effect on germination first. UMass offers a hot water seed
        treatment service.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_3">Fumigate or steam sterilize soil in seedbeds and use clean, sterilized
        seed flats.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_4">Avoid planting in areas that receive run-off from areas previously
        planted to crucifers.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_5">Increase spacing between plants to decrease leaf wetness period and
        likelihood of infection.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_6">Monitor transplants and promptly remove and destroy infected
        seedlings.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_7">Do not trim seedlings, as the bacteria are easily spread by
        contaminated tools.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_8">Practice a three-year rotation and control cruciferous weeds.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_9">Do not work in fields when they are wet and avoid overhead
        irrigation.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_10">Do not locate cull piles near fields or storage areas.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_11">Promptly incorporate crop residues after harvest to speed
        decomposition.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_black_rot_12">Bactericides are only marginally effective; sanitation and
        environmental management are important disease management principles.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_black_rot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_bacteria</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_blast">caused by the fungus Magnaporthe oryzae. It occurs in areas with low soil
        moisture, frequent and prolonged periods of rain shower, and cool temperature in the daytime. In upland rice,
        large day-night temperature differences that cause dew formation on leaves and overall cooler temperatures favor
        the development of the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_blast_1">Some resemble diamond shape, wide in the center and pointed toward either
        ends.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_blast_2">Lesions can enlarge and coalesce, growing together, to kill the entire
        leaves. Leaf blast lesions are usually elongated and pointed at each end
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_blast_3">Initial symptoms appear as white to gray-green lesions or spots, with dark
        green borders.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_blast_4">Older lesions on the leaves are elliptical or spindle-shaped and whitish to
        gray centers with red to brownish or necrotic border.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_blast_1">Adjust planting time. Sow seeds early, when possible, after the onset of
        the rainy season.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_blast_2">Split nitrogen fertilizer application in two or more treatments. Excessive
        use of fertilizer can increase blast intensity.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_blast_3">Flood the field as often as possible.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_blast_4">Silicon fertilizers (e.g., calcium silicate) can be applied to soils that
        are silicon deficient to reduce blast. However, because of its high cost, silicon should be applied efficiently.
        Cheap sources of silicon, such as straws of rice genotypes with high silicon content, can be an alternative.
        Care should be taken to ensure that the straw is free from blast as the fungus can survive on rice straw and the
        use of infected straw as a silicon source can spread the disease further.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_blast_5">Systemic fungicides like triazoles and strobilurins can be used judiciously
        for control to control blast. A fungicide application at heading can be effective in controlling the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_blast" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_brown_leaf_spot">Brown leaf spot (BLS) disease is caused by a fungus. It is one of the
        worst fungal diseases of cassava. BLS disease appears as small brown spots with dark borders on the upper leaf
        surface. The brown spots form between leaf veins so their size and shape are limited by the veins. The center of
        the brown spots may fall out leaving a hole in the leaf. During a bad attack the infected leaves become yellow
        and dry, and may die early. The disease can greatly reduce yields.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_brown_leaf_spot_1">The disease usually occurs on the older, lower leaves, and is more
        noticeable 5-6 months after planting.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_brown_leaf_spot_2">Leaves fall prematurely. Leaf spots are circular, up to 15 mm
        diameter, becoming angular and limited by veins.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_brown_leaf_spot_3">The spots are brown on upper surfaces with dark borders, sometimes
        surrounded by indistinct yellow margins. On the underside, the spots are grey with less distinct borders.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_brown_leaf_spot_4">Minor veins crossing the spots appear as black necrotic lines. The
        centres of the spots dry, crack and may fall out. As the spots enlarge, the leaves yellow and fall off.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_brown_leaf_spot_5">Warm, humid weather increases the severity of the disease. Spores
        of the fungus produced on the lower surface are spread by wind and water-splash.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_brown_leaf_spot_6">Long distance spread occurs when spores are carried on planting
        material. In general, older leaves are more susceptible to the disease The fungus can continue to live on old
        fallen leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_brown_leaf_spot_1">Plant at wide spacing, allowing the wind to dry the leaves as
        quickly as possible.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_brown_leaf_spot_2">Practice crop rotations of 3–5 years.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_brown_leaf_spot_3">Plant in the wet season, so that crops are in the susceptible
        stage (6-8-months-old) in the dry season.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_brown_leaf_spot_4">Do not plant new crops next to old ones with the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_brown_leaf_spot_5">During the dry season remove heavily diseased leaves to prevent
        the fungus spreading quickly when the rains start.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_brown_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_downy_mildew">This disease is caused by the fungus Hyloperonospora brassicae and can
        attack both seedlings and mature vegetable plants.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_downy_mildew_1">Infected plants develop a gray mold on the lower leaf surface.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_downy_mildew_2">The upper leaf surface of infected plants first turns yellow and then
        may turn brown or necrotic. Leaves wither and die.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_downy_mildew_3">Development of the disease is favored by moist conditions.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_downy_mildew_1">Use varieties with resistance or tolerance to this disease. Rotate
        with crops other than cole crops or greens.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_downy_mildew_2">Remove plant debris immediately after harvest. Use wide plant
        spacing to promote drying of leaves.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_downy_mildew_3">Avoid wetting the leaves when watering. If the disease becomes
        severe enough to warrant chemical control, chlorothalonil or mancozeb will give good control, and copper
        fungicides will give fair control.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_downy_mildew_4">Spray every seven to 10 days after transplants are set. Make sure
        that the lower leaf surface is covered with fungicide.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_downy_mildew_5">Do not apply copper when temperatures are above 90 °F. Wait 7 days
        after spraying before harvesting if using chlorothalonil or mancozeb. See Table 2 for examples of products
        containing these fungicides.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_downy_mildew_6">Apply all chemicals according to directions on the label.</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_downy_mildew" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_lace_wing">The adults are yellow to whitish and about 4 mm in size with translucent,
        fringed lace-like wings. The female beetle lays about 30 eggs on the lower leaf side. After about 12 days the
        yellow nymphs hatch. This development stage lasts for about 13 days. Currently, there is no detailed information
        available regarding yield losses due to banana lace wing bug infestation. Until now, there are no reports about
        serious damage on banana plants caused by the pest.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_lace_wing_1">The infestation is visible on the leaves, even from a distance. The
        adults and nymphs are located on the lower leaf side, where they live in colonies and feed on the leaves. Most
        commonly, the insects feed on the leaf sap around the middle vein. The feeding damage appears as tiny white,
        chlorotic spots on the upper leaf side. Dark insect secretions are left on the lower leaf surface. The colonized
        areas turn yellow to brown over time and dry out. Trees have stunted growth and look sickly.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_lace_wing_1">Predatory insect species such as Stethoconus praefectus may reduce the
        infestation if used in an integrated approach. An emulsion of neem oil and garlic (2%) can be used as foliar
        spray applications to control the infestation.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_lace_wing_2">Plant tolerant or resistant varieties if available</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_lace_wing_3">Check your plants or fields regularly for any sign of the pest</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_lace_wing_4">Handpick and destroy the first infested outer whorl of leaves in the
        field to curb the progression of the infestation
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_lace_wing" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_leaf_miner">Symptoms are caused by several flies belonging to the family of the
        Agromyzidae, with several thousand species worldwide. In spring, females puncture leaf tissues and lay their
        eggs, usually along the margins. The larvae feed between the upper and the lower leaf surface. They produce
        large white meandering tunnels with a trail of black frass left behind as they feed. Once they have reached
        maturity, larvae open a hole on the underside of the leaf and fall to the ground, where they pupate. Plant
        debris near the host are alternative pupating places. Leaf miner flies are attracted to the color yellow.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_miner_1">Irregular or serpentine pale grey lines appear on both sides of the leaf
        blades as the larvae feed. These burrows are usually limited by the leaf veins and contain black fecal material
        visible as slim traces inside the tunnels. Entire leaves may be covered with mines. Damaged leaves may drop
        prematurely (defoliation). Defoliation can reduce yield and fruit size and expose fruit to sunburn. Should not
        be confused with Tuta absoluta (Tomato Leafminer) whose mines on leaves are wider and white or transparent.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_1">Favor crop varieties with curled leaves</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_2">Check transplants for leaf miners or mines before planting</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_3">Destroy any transplants that are infested</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_4">Monitor weekly and at all growth stages of the crop</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_5">Look for tiny tunnels and larvae inside the tunnels on the upper leaf
        sides
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_6">Use glue traps or yellow sticky traps to detect leaf miners</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_7">At 8 to 12 infected plants per 100 plants, consider direct control
        action
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_8">Handpick heavily-infested leaves, and destroy them by crushing or
        burying them, or feedin them to cattle if palatable.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_9">Destroy and bury the remains of weeds and dying crops</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_miner_10">Remove crop debris immediately after harvest is finished</string>
    <string name="disease_vector_leaf_miner" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_leaf_mosaic">Cassava mosaic virus disease is a viral disease which is carried by insects
        such as whiteflies. When the whiteflies suck sap from the plant, they pick up the virus, and then transport and
        inject it when feeding on the next plant. To avoid the spread of the disease to healthy plants, the infected
        plants must be uprooted and destroyed. There is no agrochemical that can control the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mosaic_1">The disease causes curling of leaves and the formation of
        yellow-greenish or white-greenish patches within the green leaf which is known as chlorosis or mosaic.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mosaic_2">When the disease is severe, the new leaves are small and distorted and
        the plants become stunted.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_leaf_mosaic_3">Totally yellow leaves of normal size or brown leaves are not a sign of
        this disease. Wild cassava (kisamvu cha mpira in Kiswahili) also hosts the disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_1">Do not plant cassava close to infected fields as the insect vectors
        will transport the disease to healthy plants
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_2">Keep the insect vectors that carry the disease away from the field by
        surrounding it with a clear boarder of no vegetation (2 to 3 metres wide). Slash all bushes.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_3">Observe plants for disease symptoms once a week for the first 2 to 3
        months after planting. When 2 to 5 plants with disease symptoms are found in your field, prepare for uprooting
        process.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_4">Prepare healthy cassava cuttings which will be used to replace the
        diseased cassava plants.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_5">The length of each cutting should be 15 to 20cm.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_6">The uprooting process of diseased plants starts 2 to 3 weeks after
        the previously planted cuttings have sprout.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_7">Two people should be involved, with one person searching and
        uprooting the diseased plants while the other person plants new healthy cassava cuttings. The uprooting person
        should not touch the new clean plantings and the planting person should not touch the diseased plants.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_8">Uproot diseased plants once every week by pulling them out by hand.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_9">The uprooted plants should be carried away from the field and exposed
        to the sunlight for drying and then burned to kill the viruses. Do not bury the diseased materials in a field.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_leaf_mosaic_10">The number of diseased plants is reduced as the exercise is
        repeated.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_leaf_mosaic" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_virus</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_mealybug_wilt">The disease causes a reddening (later pink), severe tip dieback, downward
        curling and wilting of the leaves; there is also a collapse of the roots Recovery can occur, but fruits are
        small. Pineapple wilt appears to be influenced by age of the plants: young plants develop symptoms in 2-3
        months; older plants take up to a year. The disease is associated with the mealybugs, Dysmicoccus brevipes (pink
        mealybug) and Dysmicoccus neobrevipes (grey mealybug) mealybugs feed on pineapples, acquire Pineapple mealybug
        wilt-associated virus(es) and then pass the viruses to other plants.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_mealybug_wilt_1">The initial focus of infection usually occurs near the field edges
        and spreads inward.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_mealybug_wilt_2">The disease is characterized by preliminary leaf-tip die back and
        reddening along the leaf length.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_mealybug_wilt_3">This is followed by a progressive change of leaf colour from red to
        pink, inward reflexing of the leaf margin, loss of rigidity and the eventual collapse of the leaves along most
        of their length.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_mealybug_wilt_4">The roots cease to grow, causing the plant to wilt (Carter, 1944,
        1948; Samson, 1986). Plants affected during the early stage of growth do not form fruits, or produce small
        fruits. Some plants, even those that appear fully wilted, may undergo an apparent recovery, during which the
        oldest symptomatic leaves senesce, younger symptomatic leaves grow out and wilt at the tip and new growth
        appears normal.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_mealybug_wilt_5">These plants can produce healthy fruits and crowns.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_1">Use plants that have been treated to free them from virus (hot
        water or tissue culture) or selected from fields where the incidence of pineapple wilt is low
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_2">Use plants grown from axillary or apical buds in tissue culture,
        and tested for the presence of Pineapple mealybug wilt-associated virus(es)
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_3">Hot water treatment. Place crowns or slips in water at 50°C for 30
        mins. This has been used as a treatment to produce planting material free from Pineapple mealybug
        wilt-associated virus(es)
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_4" formatted="false">Use planting material from wilt-free areas or
        from fields where
        there is less than 10% of plants with pineapple wilt. Remove and destroy diseased plants before taking planting
        material. Additionally, do not take
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_5">Do not plant new pineapple crops next to those where pineapple wilt
        occurs. Never plant pineapples on land where the disease was present previously. If crops are heavily infested,
        remove and burn them, and plough the land, leaving it fallow until all the debris has been plough in or has
        decomposed.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_6">Cultivate the soil to destroy colonies of the big-headed ant
        (Pheidole); nests are near the soil surface, and re-invasion from surrounding areas is slow.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_7">Decide on plant density. Different bed configurations are used:
        single, two, or four rows and then a gap. Note, the higher the density (i.e., four adjacent rows before a gap)
        the easier it is for mealybugs to spread by leaf-to-leaf contact.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_8">Remove plants with symptoms of pineapple wilt as soon as they are
        seen and burn them.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_mealybug_wilt_9">Keep borders free from weeds that may harbour mealybugs and ants.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_mealybug_wilt" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_pineapple_heart_rot">Heart and root rots of pineapple (Ananas comosusL.) in Hawaii are
        caused by several species of the plant-pathogenic water molds Pythium and Phytophthora. These soil-borne
        organisms cause severe diseases of many crops worldwide, including pineapple. Heart rot affects the basal leaf
        tissues and can rot fruit as well, while root rot causes root necrosis that, if left unaddressed, may lead to
        reduced crop yields and total crops failure.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_pineapple_heart_rot_1">Young leaves failing to elongate and turning chlorotic; heart
        leaves wilting and turning brown
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_pineapple_heart_rot_2">terminal whorl can be easily pulled from mother plant;
        water-soaked tissue at base of leaves
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_pineapple_heart_rot_3">foul smell; leaves may be turning red and yellow with necrotic
        leaf margins and leaf tips; plants can easily be pulled out of the ground; fruits color prematurely
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_pineapple_heart_rot_1">Plant the crop on well drained non-heavy soils, and not in
        low land.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_pineapple_heart_rot_2">Raise planting beds at least 23 cm high for settling of the
        plant. Between raised beds, build trenches to get rid of excess water without causing soil erosion. Deep rip
        down the slope before hilling if soil is compact.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_pineapple_heart_rot_3">Plant disease free planting materials Practice plant space of
        at least 60 cm Apply phosphorus fertilizers to strengthen plant. Avoid evening irrigation, as moisture cannot
        dry on leaves. Avoid overhead irrigation to minimize splashes. Avoid flooding or furrow irrigation otherwise
        disease will be carried over. Only irrigate from healthy to unhealthy crop areas.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_pineapple_heart_rot_4">Mulch and re-mulch with any dry plant debris except from
        pineapples to reduce muddy conditions.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_pineapple_heart_rot_5">Remove pineapple residue after harvest, and leave in sun to
        reduce disease. However, if no major insect pests and diseases are in your crop, then leave the residues to
        improve the soil, and reduce water evaporation.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_pineapple_heart_rot_6">After heavy rot disease infestation, do not grow pineapples
        for several years on the same plot.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_pineapple_heart_rot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_rust_thrips">The infestation can occur at any growth stage and is visible on leaves,
        pseudostems and fruits. Adults and larvae usually settle behind the bases of leaf sheaths. Nymphs are gregarious
        and feed by sucking the plant sap with their mouthparts. Initial symptoms appear as water-soaked areas on
        fruits. Over time, these areas give the fruits a characteristic rusty aspect, with deep red to dark brown
        colored skin. Usually, only the peel shows damage, but if infestation is heavy the whole fruit can show signs of
        damage. On more mature fruits, cracks may be visible. Sometimes the fruits split open. The infestation is most
        harmful to fruit bunches when infested in early development stages.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_rust_thrips_1">Symptoms are caused mainly by the thrips Chaetanaphothrips signipennis,
        but other species may also be involved (Helionothrips kadaliphilus). The pest is most commonly transmitted via
        infested plant material, or to a lesser degree directly by the insects flying between trees. Adults are slim,
        yellow to brown, about 1.3 mm in size and have narrow fringed wings with two dark areas on the forewings. The
        female lays tiny eggs (not visible to the naked eye) on the under leaf sheaths and where fruits touch the plant.
        After about 7 days, the wingless, white to cream larvae hatch. They grow to the size of adults within about 7
        days. Then they move to the ground, enter the soil on the plant base and pupate. After an additional 7-10 days,
        the new generation of adult thrips hatches. There can be many generations per year. During hot and humid weather
        there can be population peaks.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_rust_thrips_1">Use healthy planting material from certified sources</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_rust_thrips_2">Remove volunteer plants and avoid cultivating host plants around the
        main crop field
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_rust_thrips_3">Check your plants or fields periodically for any sign of the pest.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_rust_thrips_4">Remove infested plants and destroy by burning</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_rust_thrips_5">Remove abandoned plantation areas as these can serve as sources for
        pest spreading.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_rust_thrips" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_sigatoka_leaf_spot">caused by Pseudocercospora musicola (formerly Mycosphaerella
        musicola)
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_sigatoka_leaf_spot_1">The first visible symptom is a slight discoloration between the
        leaf\'s secondary veins. Over time, these points develop into pale yellow streaks, brown streaks and elliptic
        necrotic spots arranged parallel to the secondary veins. The depressed grey center is surrounded by a yellow
        halo. As the disease progresses, the lesions coalesce and cover a large area of the leaf
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_sigatoka_leaf_spot_1">The fungicides used to control black leaf streak can also be
        used against Sigatoka leaf spot. It is recommended to alternate between systemic and contact fungicides to delay
        the development of resistance to the fungicides. A forecasting system has been developed for Sigatoka leaf spot.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_sigatoka_leaf_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_sooty_mold">Fungi that cause sooty mold do not attack plants directly, but obtain their
        nutrients from the honeydew itself. Although the fungi do not feed on the plants, they can indirectly destroy
        the beauty of the plant and, if the concentration of the mold is heavy enough, shade out enough light to yellow
        and stunt the plant. In severe cases, the plant or plant parts may die, but this is probably due to damage
        caused by the insects.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_sooty_mold_1">Sooty mold is usually a black powdery coating that develops on leaves
        and twigs.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_sooty_mold_2">Sometimes the black layer may be hard and stick tightly to the leaf.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_sooty_mold_3">During spring rains, the black layer may flake off or peel a</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_sooty_mold_4">way from part of the leaf, leaving healthy looking green areas with
        splotches of the black sooty mold
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_sooty_mold_1">The first step in control of sooty molds is to suppress the aphids,
        scales, or other pests that are excreting the honeydew on which sooty molds subsist.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_sooty_mold_2">If one of the horticultural oils is used for control, it also has the
        advantage of helping to loosen sooty molds from the plant surface.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_sooty_mold_3">This hastens the weathering away of the sooty molds.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_sooty_mold_4">Horticultural oils are formulated by many companies are available
        through garden centers, hardware stores, and like establishments.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_sooty_mold" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_southern_blight">Caused by the fungus Sclerotium rolfsii, Okra and tomatoes are not the
        only plants to be susceptible to this fungus. It actually throws a wide net, encompassing at least 500 species
        in 100 families with curcurbits, crucifers, and legumes being its most common targets.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_southern_blight_1">A yellowing of the foliage with slight darkening of the stem just
        above the soil line.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_southern_blight_2">Lesions on the stem at or near the soil line develop rapidly,
        girdling the stem and causing sudden and permanent wilt of the plant.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_southern_blight_3">The fungus grows downward in the stem and root, rotting the
        cortical tissue. White mats of mycelium develop on the stem and nearby soil.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_southern_blight_4">In a few days, tan to brown spherical sclerotia (tiny compact
        masses of hardened fungal mycelium) appear on the mycelial mat. The sclerotia are a good diagnostic feature of
        this disease.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_southern_blight_1">Practice good garden sanitation. Keep your garden free of weeds
        and plant debris and decay.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_southern_blight_2">Remove and destroy infected okra plant matter immediately (do not
        compost). If the sclerotia seed-bodies have set, you will need to clean them all up as well as remove the top
        few inches (5 to 10 cm.) of soil in the affected area. Avoid overwatering.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_southern_blight_3">When watering, try doing so early in the day and consider the use
        of drip irrigation to ensure you are only watering at the base of the okra plant. This helps to keep your
        foliage drier.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_southern_blight_4">Use a fungicide. If you are not opposed to chemical solutions,
        you may want to consider a soil drench with the fungicide Terrachlor, which is available to home gardeners and
        is probably the most effective means of treating okra with southern blight.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_southern_blight" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_fungi</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_tobacco_caterpillar">Symptoms are caused by the larvae of Spodotpera litura. Adult moths
        have grayish-brown bodies and variegated forewings with white wavy markings on the edges. The hindwings are
        translucent white with brown lines along the margins and the veins. Females lay hundreds of eggs in clusters on
        the upper leaf blades, covered with golden brown scales. After hatching, the hairless light-green larvae
        disperse quickly and start feeding gregariously on leaves. Older larvae are dark green to brown with dark spots
        on the flanks and somewhat clearer bellies. Two yellow longitudinal bands run along the sides, interrupted by
        black triangular spots. An orange band runs dorsally between these spots. Larvae feed during the night and take
        refuge in the soil during the day. Larvae and adults thrive at temperatures between 15°C and 35°C, optimum at 25
        °C. Low humidity and higher or lower temperatures reduce fertility and prolong their life cycle.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tobacco_caterpillar_1">Feeding damage becomes apparent on the leaves. Larvae are
        scraping the leaf tissue, creating large, irregular shaped holes. It can result in complete defoliation of the
        plant. Flower buds and pods are also attacked and show feeding holes. In lighter soils also the roots become
        damaged. Due to extensive feeding, only petioles and branches are left behind.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tobacco_caterpillar_1" formatted="false">Bioinsecticides based on Nuclear
        Polyhedrosis Virus (NPV) or
        Bacillus thuringiensis can be used on eggs and larvae. Bait solutions based on rice bran, molasses or brown
        sugar can be distributed on the soil in the evening hours. Plant oil extracts of neem leaves or kernels and
        extracts of Pongamia glabra seeds are highly effective against Spodoptera litura larvae. For example,
        azadirachtin 1500 ppm (5 ml/l) or NSKE 5% can be used during the egg stage and prevents the egg from hatching.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_tobacco_caterpillar" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_tungro">Transplanting seedlings from nurseries in tungro-infected areas has also shown
        to increase infection rates in the field, particularly, in cases where seedbed is in a tungro-endemic area or
        when the nursery duration is 5−6 weeks.However, this is not believed to be a very strong mechanism in initiating
        epidemics, because the competitiveness of tungro-infected seedlings is low; they can die rapidly after
        transplanting.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_1">Check for the presence of leafhoppers.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_2">Check leaves for discoloration.</string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_3">Yellow or orange-yellow discoloration is noticeable in tungro-infected
        plants. Discoloration begins from the leaf tip and extends down to the blade or the lower leaf portion. Infected
        leaves may also show mottled or striped appearance, rust-colored spots, and inter-veinal necrosis.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_4">The degree of stunting and of leaf discoloration varies with rice varieties,
        strains of the viruses, the age of the plant when infected, and with the environment. In varieties that carry
        some resistance to the disease, infected plants exhibit no discoloration or only a mild discoloration that may
        disappear as the plants mature.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_5">Tungro symptoms can be mistaken for physiological disorders. Specifically,
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_6">pest infestation such as stem borer infestation, planthopper infestation,
        and rat damage
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_tungro_7">other diseases such as grassy stunt virus disease and orange leaf.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tungro_1">Grow tungro or leafhopper resistant varieties. This is the most economical
        means of managing the disease. There are tungro-resistant varieties available for the Philippines, Malaysia,
        Indonesia, India, and Bangladesh.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tungro_2">Contact your local agriculture office for up-to-date lists of varieties
        available.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tungro_3">Practice synchronous planting with surrounding farms.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tungro_4">Delayed or late planting, relative to the average date in a given area,
        makes the field susceptible for Tungro. Late-planted fields also pose a risk to early planting in the next
        season.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tungro_5">Adjust planting times to when green leafhopper are not in season or
        abundant, if known
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_tungro_6">Plow infected stubbles immediately after harvest to reduce inoculum
        sources and destroy the eggs and breeding sites of green leaf hoppers.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_tungro" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="disease_cause_yellow_spot">The viruses are transmitted to pineapple plants by small flying insects
        (thrips). Infection occurs mostly on plants during early growth, and crowns on developing fruit are occasionally
        infected. As infection is always fatal, vegetable propagation does the virus to subsequent plantings.
        Tospoviruses have a wide range of host among weed and crop plants. The disease is rarely seen.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_yellow_spot_1">Infection occurs on young crowns when they are still on the fruit or
        during the first few months after planting.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_yellow_spot_2">Small (2-5 mm), round, yellow spots appear on the upper surface of the
        leaves of young plants.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_yellow_spot_3">These spots fuse and form yellow streaks in the leaf tissue, which soon
        become brown and die.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_symptom_yellow_spot_4">The virus spread on the leaves in the plant heart, causing the plant to
        bend sideways. Infection eventually kills the plant so that the virus is not transmitted to subsequent planting.
        If crown in infections can occur though open blossoms causing the development of large, blacked cavities in the
        side of the fruit.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_yellow_spot_1">Keep the plantation free from weeds.</string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_yellow_spot_2">Avoid destroying old weedy patches near young crown planting or field
        with developing fruit.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_treatment_yellow_spot_3">If this is impossible, it may be necessary to first spray the old
        infected field to control thrips.
    </string>
    <string name="disease_vector_yellow_spot" translatable="false">@string/val_vector_pest</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_learn_more">Frequently asked questions (FAQs)</string>
    <string name="ui_head_learn_more">About this app</string>
    <string name="ui_text_head_learn">Can\'t find what you\'re looking for?</string>
    <string name="ui_text_desc_learn">Avail the laboratory services:\nDepartment of Agriculture\nCapitol Rd., Brgy.
        Mankilam, Tagum City\nFor more info, visit www.davaodelnorte.gov.ph
    </string>
    <string name="ui_text_head_supported">What crops and diseases are supported?</string>
    <string name="ui_text_learn_header" translatable="false">capitol_overhead</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_verify_email">Verification email sent to</string>
    <string name="ui_head_verify_email">Email Verification</string>
    <string name="ui_text_logout_instead">Logout instead</string>
    <string name="ui_text_warn_logout">Logged out</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_password_fail_capital">Password must contain one capital letter</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_password_fail_numeral">Password must contain one digit</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_sent_verify_email">Verification email sent to</string>
    <string name="ui_text_disease">disease</string>
    <string name="ui_text_leaf">leaf</string>
    <string name="ui_text_learn_more">Learn More</string>
    <string name="ui_warn_landscape">Diagnosis history minimized in landscape mode</string>
    <string name="ui_desc_onboarding" translatable="false">Image Onboarding</string>
    <string name="fui_start_default" translatable="false">Start</string>
    <string name="ui_text_show_more">Show more</string>

</resources>